Ashwani Kumar V

Senior DevOps Engineer

**** +91 7989 121 975

✓ avardhineni7@gmail.com

♀ Hyderabad, IN

Social Proof

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>GitHub</u>

SUMMARY

9+ years of experience in IT field which includes 6+ years in handling AWS Cloud environments, Build and Administer Micro-Services architecture through K8S & AWS EKS.

Proficiency in working in DevOps lifecycle management environment, creating build & release pipelines, Infrastructure Automation & Configuration Management in multiple environments.

Analytical, committed, persistent individual and reliable team member. Continuously learning and acquiring new knowledge and skills.

KEY SKILLS

Linux System Administration
Bash, Python Scripting
AWS Cloud
AWS Security, DevSecOps
Terraform
Ansible, Packer
Git/Git Hub, Bitbucket, Code
Commit
Maven, JFrog, Sonarqube
Nginx, Apache Tomcat
Jenkins, CodeBuild
Docker, CodeDeploy

Kubernetes, AWS EKS

Helm Charts, CodePipeline

AWS Cloud Administration, Terraform & Ansible Automation, Kubernetes Admin with DevOps Lifecycle

Professional Experience

Senior Cloud Engineer, Visionet Systems Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru Date: July 2021 – Till date

Job Profile: Build and Release Management, Deployment Automation, and Kubernetes Administration.

Cloud Engineer, TCS, Hyderabad

Payroll: Ivytel Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Bengaluru,

Date: January 2018 - July 2021

Job Profile: AWS Administration & Infrastructure Automation

Module Lead, Mindtree LTD. Hyderabad, Client: Microsoft, Hyderabad

Date: February 2015 - December 2017

Job Profile: O365 Migrations & Administration

Messaging Server Engineer, Aster Minds Enterprise Solutions Pvt. Ltd. Hyderabad,

Client: Microsoft, Bangalore Date: May 2014 - February 2015

Job Profile: Exchange Server Migrations

Server Engineer (L3), Zenith InfoTech Pvt. Ltd. Mumbai,

Date: July 2012 - May 2014

Job Profile: Exchange Server Administration

Roles and Responsibilities

- 1. **Collaborate with software product development,** architecture, and IT teams to ensure releases are **delivered with repeatable and auditable** processes.
- 2. Responsible for **application Build & Release process** which includes Code Compilation, **Packaging, Security Scanning and code quality scanning**, Deployment Methodology and Application Configurations.
- 3. Architect and design the setup and configuration of CI/CD pipelines and support/resolve technical complexities to integrate various DevOps practices as part of CI/CD implementation.
- 4. Work closely with product teams to find the right trade-off between business-specific needs and state-of-the-art CI/CD best practices.
- 5. Build and maintain tools for **deployment**, **monitoring**, and **operations**.
- 6. Execute and automate operational processes quickly, accurately, and securely. **Provide solutions to increase visualization, reduce errors**, and **improve customer experience**.
- 7. **Support and troubleshoot scalability, high availability**, performance, monitoring, **backup, and restoration** of different environments.
- 8. Troubleshoot and **resolve issues in our development**, test, and production environments.
- 9. Evaluate **new tools, technologies, and processe**s to improve the speed, efficiency, and **scalability of continuous integration** environments.
- 10. Used **Jira as a Change Management**/ Work Management/ **Scrum Agile** Tool. **Updating the application team** in order to track the status of the user stories or defects.

Prometheus & Grafana CloudWatch AWS Lambda, API Gateway JIRA

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate Hashicorp Certified - Terraform Associate

EDUCATION

Education History

Skills and Experience

- 1. Embedding **Security** at every step of **SDLC** with various **DevSecOps tools**.
- 2. Expertise in **deploying at scale** various **containerized web**, **data applications**, and services using technologies such as **Docker**, **Kubernetes**, Elastic Kubernetes Service (**EKS**), Elastic Container Service (**ECS**), CloudWatch, and other **monitoring solutions**.
- 3. Strong experience in **40+ AWS services** such as EC2, ELB ALB & NLB, ASG, IAM, CloudWatch, Relational Database Service (RDS), S3, etc.
- 4. Configured **AWS Security Services** such as IAM, KMS, ACM, WAF, Inspector, Trusted Advisor, Cloud Trail, Config, and Guard Duty to secure resources at multiple layers.
- 5. Used **Terraform to build** multiple environments such as Dev, Staging and Prod using AWS DevOps workflow.
- 6. Standardized the **Terraform modules** for all the resources in AWS Cloud. This helped in **reducing the code time** and re-usability of the modules.
- 7. Automated the **creation of Golden AMI** through **Packer** and used **Ansible** for **Application configuration**.
- 8. Used **Jenkins Pipelines** to drive all **Micro Services** builds out to the Docker/ECR registry and then **deployed to Kubernetes**/ECS/EKS, and managed the application with **various Kubernetes Objects** also **integrated** with **Jira and Slack to send** build state information.
- 9. **Optimize Jenkins container configurations** such as mount docker runtime inside **container as a volume**, fixing permissions on docker.sock, and **scripted Jenkins configurations** in to a Jenkinsfile to run **Single Pipeline** and **MultiBranch** Pipeline Jobs.
- 10. Experience in **administering Kubernetes** and a good understanding of manifest management with Helm along with expertise in Ingress Controller and Service mesh with **Istio for pod communication and encryption**.
- 11. Used **Terraform to automate** the EKS Cluster and integrated Terraform in **CI/CD Pipelines** to automate provisioning of Servers.
- 12. Automated tasks related to System Health Checks, Monitoring and Remote Administration, Backup and Restore, Scheduled tasks, Clean-up, Data Visualizations, Send Notifications, CI/CD related tasks through Python Scripting.
- 13. Expert in using **ELK Stack**; **ElasticSearch** for deep search and data analytics, **fluentD** for centralized logging, log enrichment and parsing and **Kibana for powerful** and beautiful data visualizations.
- 14. Used **Jira as change Management** and **Scrum Agile** tool. Updating the application team in order to track the status of the **user stories or defects**.
- 15. Configured **Prometheus Server** and its **components such as** Grafana, Alertmanager, ServiceMonitor, Prometheus Rules to monitor all Cluster Nodes, K8S Components, Microservices Applications, Redis Data broker.
- 16. Successfully **upgraded the Kubernetes and Jenkins** by following the best practices and Effectively took the **back up of ETCD** database and performed timely **restore drills**.
- 17. Performed **Cost optimization with Kubecost** to avoid overspending on the resources.

Looking Forward To Learn

- 1. Azure Cloud, Azure DevOps, GCP
- 2. New DevOps and DevSecOps tools that emerge during my DevOps Engineer Journey.